people who are predisposed to getting
acne um will often get a increase in
acne I guess outbreaks or occurrence
whatever the the correct term for that
is because when DHT increases uh rapidly
it will increase the production of of
sebum um and this will essentially I
mean you can correct from a wrong here
um but this will cause the uh if it dis
that the body is usually making the core
is the the pore is more prone to getting
clogged which will lead to acne so it's
hormone fluctuations that are
problematic it's why women will be
predisposed to acne around their cycle
it's not necessarily where the hormones
are it's the changing in hormones so
change will induce this for guys who are
predisposed to it and um I understand
that it sucks I I've been very I guess
blessed that I've never really dealt
with acne my whole life personally so
it's something that you know I'm I'm
very grateful for that but you know
especially when guys get it very bad on
their face or on their upper body and it
scars it can be quite distressing um and
you know looking at what they can do to
support their diet support their Liver
Health support their hydration you know
removing things that are inflammatory to
the gut can often be really helpful and
the the biggest thing that I've seen
help a lot in Australia in terms of just
what's you know common with with the
guys who I work with is if you wear like
a polyester like shirt and you sweat
into it at work that can be quite you
know that can annoy the skin quite a bit
so getting like a cotton undershirt if
you sweat into a polyester work uniform
or if you're wearing polyester like
active wear to the gym that can getting
rid of that can be really helpful too
[Music]